<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Xiaoyu Xie&#39;s Blog</title>
  
  <subtitle>Machine Learning, Deep Learning, Computer Vision</subtitle>
  <link href="http://example.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  
  <link href="http://example.com/"/>
  <updated>2022-12-26T15:38:50.751Z</updated>
  <id>http://example.com/</id>
  
  <author>
    <name>Xiaoyu Xie</name>
    
  </author>
  
  <generator uri="https://hexo.io/">Hexo</generator>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Xiaoyu Xie</title>
    <link href="http://example.com/2022/02/25/index/"/>
    <id>http://example.com/2022/02/25/index/</id>
    <published>2022-02-26T01:19:13.000Z</published>
    <updated>2022-12-26T15:38:50.751Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Welcome to my personal academic blog! I am Xiaoyu Xie, a third-year PhD candidate in Mechanical Engineering Department at Northwestern University. My advisor is <a href="https://www.mccormick.northwestern.edu/research-faculty/directory/profiles/liu-kam-wing.html">Prof. Wing Kam Liu</a>. In my research, I focus on developing robust and flexible artificial intelligence (AI) to uncover hidden patterns and knowledge from data in manufacturing, fluid mechanics, and solid mechanics. Through my work on scientific/mechanistic machine learning or AI4Science, I aim to improve the interpretability, generalization, and small-dataset scalability of AI algorithms by incorporating existing scientific insight. My research in dimensionless learning is a prime example of this approach, as it uses fundamental physical invariance to discover three levels of knowledge through machine learning. </p><h1 id="News"><a href="#News" class="headerlink" title="News"></a>News</h1><ul><li>[12/2022]: Our official <a href="https://xiaoyuxie.top/PyDimension-Book/intro.html"><strong>PyDimension Documentation</strong></a> for dimensionless learning was released, in which you can try different tutorials and examples interactively!</li><li>[12/2022]: Our latest work called <a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-022-35084-w#Sec2"><strong>“Data-driven discovery of dimensionless numbers and governing laws from scarce measurements”</strong></a> was published on <strong><em>Nature Communications</em></strong>!</li><li>[08/2022]: Our team won <strong>three 1st places</strong> and <strong>two 2nd places</strong> in Additive Manufacturing Benchmark Challenge (AM-Bench), NIST, US, 2022!</li></ul>]]></content>
    
    
      
      
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Welcome to my personal academic blog! I am Xiaoyu Xie, a third-year PhD candidate in Mechanical Engineering Department at Northwestern Un</summary>
      
    
    
    
    
  </entry>
  
</feed>
